Guide to the Frank Espada photographs and papers, 1946-2010 and undated, bulk 1975-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Manuscript Materials Series, 1989-2005 and undated, (6 boxes)
  Another large sub-series includes materials from the preparations and edits for Espada's book, The Puerto Rican Diaspora: Themes in the Survival of a People, which was published in 2006.
  The supporting documentation for the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project offers insight into the work done by Espada to win the grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities, as well as the work he completed during the grant period through site visits, newsletters, and reports. Several folders relate to interviews, including some summaries, quotes, and transcripts. The audiocassette tapes for these interviews are a separate series in the collection. Another component of this subseries is the exhibit preparation and logistics: the project was exhibited in 45 venues over a 15 year period. Finally, there is third-party supporting documentation about Puerto Rico and the various communities highlighted by Espada in the project.
  The Chamorro Documentary Project materials, dating 1989-1990, include information about the different locations photographed by Espada, as well as notebooks and exhibit materials.
  The remainder of the series includes some supporting documentation about some of Espada's other projects, including HIV/AIDS outreach, Civil Rights, and the Real Alternatives Program. Other materials honor Espada, including some city proclamations.
  - Teaching Materials
    - Documentary Portraiture, slides, 1990 (Box 24)
    - Advanced Photography, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Fall 1997 (Box 24)
    - Advanced Documentary Projects, at the Academy of Art College, Spring 1994 (Box 24)
    - Advanced Black and White Photography, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Fall 1989 (Box 24)
    - The Photo Essay workshop, 2005 (Box 24)
    - Making Excellent Negatives workshop, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Aesthetics seminar and workshop, Fall 1998 (Box 24)
    - Street Photography workshop, 2005 (Box 24)
    - Black and White Darkroom Technique, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Spring 1989 (Box 24)
    - Advanced Black and White Photography, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Fall 1990 (Box 24)
    - Aesthetics and Ethics seminars, May-June 1991 (Box 24)
    - Black and White Darkroom Technique, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Spring 1994 (Box 25)
    - The Photo Essay, at the Academy of Art College, Spring 1996 (Box 25)
    - Advanced Black and White Photography, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Fall 1991 (Box 25)
    - Fine Print workshop, July 1995 (Box 25)
    - Advanced Printing, at the Academy of Art College, Spring 2000 (Box 25)
    - Advanced Class, July 1992 (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics seminar (Box 25)
    - Evaluations, 2000 (Box 25)
    - Rosters (Box 25)
    - Seminar questionnaires, at the U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Fall 2003 (Box 25)
    - Art of the Fine Print roster, Summer 1996 (Box 25)
    - Advanced Printing, Academy of Art College, Summer 1996 (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics seminar, Spring 1997 (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics, Spring 1998 (Box 25)
    - Questionnaires, Art of the Fine Print, Spring 1995 (Box 25)
    - Seminar general (Box 25)
    - Quotes (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics seminar, 5th session handouts (Box 25)
    - On Wholeness, etc., 5th session handouts (Box 25)
    - Evaluations (Box 25)
    - Negatives worksheet handouts (Box 25)
    - Art of the Fine Print, U.C. Berkeley Extension School, Spring 1997 (Box 25)
    - Art of the Fine Print (Box 25)
    - Making Excellent Negatives (Box 25)
    - Looking at Photographs (Box 25)
    - Cartier-Bresson Profile (Box 25)
    - Art of the Fine Print, Spring 1996 (Box 25)
    - Advanced Class roster, Fall 1995 (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics workshop, Fall 1997 (Box 25)
    - Art of the Fine Print roster, Spring 1995 (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics (Box 25)
    - The Photo Essay (Box 25)
    - Documentary Portraiture (Box 25)
    - Photo Essay, Fall 2005, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Emails, 2004 (Box 25)
    - Photo Essay (Box 25)
    - Advanced seminar, 2003 (Box 25)
    - Art Statement, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Portfolio Development worksheet mailing, April 2001 (Box 25)
    - Documentary Portrait advisories (Box 25)
    - Independent Study, Spring 1997 (Box 25)
    - Photo Essay advisories, 1995 (Box 25)
    - Aesthetics and Ethics (Box 25)
    - Academy of Art College model syllabus, etc., 1997 (Box 25)
  - Book Preparation
    - Captions, 2006 (Box 25)
    - Textual pieces (Box 25)
    - Pagination (Box 25)
    - Changes to book layout, July 2006 (Box 25)
    - Copy edits from Martin, November 2006 (Box 25)
    - Documents sent to Martin for review, November 2006 (Box 25)
    - Edited copy, 14 November 2006 (Box 25)
    - Paste-ups (Box 25)
    - Book design (Box 25)
    - Book dummy (Box 25)
    - Copies of text materials (Box 25)
    - Text for book (Box 25)
    - Puerto Rico statistics (Box 25)
    - Some Diaspora documentary quotes from interviews (Box 25)
    - Seven interview narratives (Box 25)
    - Working notes for book (Box 25)
    - Galleys (Box 25)
    - Notebook (Box 25)
  - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
    - NEH
      - Grant advisory committee, 1979 (Box 26)
      - Grant concept and working papers, 1979 (Box 26)
      - Grant site folder, Midwest, 1979-1980 (Box 26)
      - Grant first advisory committee meeting, 1979 (Box 26)
      - Letter awarding grant, 1980 (Box 26)
      - National Board of Advisors, memos, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 26)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1982, (8 folders) (Box 26)
      - Letters-Academic Humanists, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - Site visits
      - Boston, 1980 (Box 26)
      - Connecticut, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - Pennsylvania, 1981 (Box 26)
      - Puerto Rico (Box 26)
    - Updates newsletter materials
      - 1980 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - 1981 (Box 26)
      - Hawaiian Experience essays, undated, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - Interviews
      - Transcripts, 1981 (Box 26)
      - Mushroom workers, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 26)
      - Summaries, (4 folders) (Box 26)
      - Quotes, 1988 (Box 26)
      - Narratives, 1980 (Box 26)
      - Interviews' drafts, 1981 (Box 26)
    - Exhibits
      - Log of images, 2006 (Box 26)
      - Captions, (4 folders) (Box 26)
      - Quotes (Box 26)
      - Text (Box 26)
      - Who am I? article by Espada, 1982 (Box 26)
      - Boricua College 10th Anniversary Report, 1984 (Box 26)
      - Exhibit announcements, 1985, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - Left Curve article, 1987 (Box 26)
      - Exhibits list and site sponsors (Box 26)
      - Exhibits, 1993-2007, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - Various correspondence, 1992-2010 (Box 26)
      - Mounted captions and quotes from exhibits (Box 34)
    - Printed Materials/Supporting Documentation
      - Tecolate article, 2007 (Box 26)
      - Puerto Rican Legal Defense Fund brochure, undated (Box 26)
      - Drug abuse prevention materials, 1970s (Box 26)
      - PROMESA publications, 1984 and undated (Box 26)
      - Voices of Protest: The Other Underclass, 1989 (Box 26)
      - Poverty Project proposal, 1991 (Box 26)
      - Dos milliones abandonados draft (Box 26)
      - Puerto Rico statistics (Box 26)
      - Housing Development and Neighborhood Preservation report, San Francisco, 1989 (Box 26)
  - Chamorro Documentary Project
    - Documentary correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 27)
    - Expense report, July 1990 (Box 27)
    - Copy-captions, introductions, sections, 1990 (Box 27)
    - Research re: Guam, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Micronesia, 1990 (Box 27)
    - Exhibit log, July 1990 (Box 27)
    - Photo notebook, 1989-1990 (Box 27)
    - Exhibit brochure (Box 27)
    - Letter from Loling, also known as Laura Marie Toures Souder, 1990 May (Box 27)
  - Other Projects
    - School boycotts 1964, 2008 (Box 27)
    - Manny, 1965 (Box 27)
    - National Civil Rights Museum (Box 27)
    - AIDS Education for youth (Box 27)
    - HIV/AIDS outreach: Mid-city project log, 1989-1990 (Box 27)
    - HIV/AIDS outreach: Society article with Espada's photographs, 1990 (Box 27)
    - HIV/AIDS outreach: YES manual for outreach to drug users, 1991 (Box 27)
    - Real Alternatives Program (RAP) School, 1986 (Box 27)
    - Quest International report and position paper, 1985-1987 (Box 28)
    - Faces of the Sixties pamphlets, 1988 (Box 28)
  - Personal Papers
    - Clippings: exhibits, news, materials about Frank Espada, 1969-1990 and undated, (5 folders) (Box 28)
    - Proclamations honoring the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project and its exhibits, 1986-1991 (Box 28)
    - What Democracy Means to Me, by Espada, 1946 (Box 28)
    - Photographs of Espada, 1969-1977, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Felicia Kornbluh's book and materials, Battle for Welfare Rights, 2004 (Box 28)
    - Lord is this a Psalm?, volume of poems by Jack Aguerros (Box 28)
    - Hanging Loose (volume of poems and fiction), 1988 (Box 28)
    - Thank you notes to Espada, 1980-2010 (Box 28)
    - Testimonials, 1999-2003 (Box 28)
    - Essays by Martin Espada, 1998-2010 and undated (Box 28)
    - Plaque: National Association of Puerto Rican Drug Abuse Programs Conference, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1979 (Box 28)
    - Plaque: Special Recognition Award for Leadership and Commitment, to the National Association of Puerto Rican Drug Abuse Programs, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1979 (Box 28)
- Photographic Prints Series, 1963-1991, (21 boxes)
  Approximately 335 large black-and-white gelatin silver prints, many matted and signed by Frank Espada. Most prints relate to the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project and contain portraits of Puerto Rican communities in New York, New Jersey, Connecticut, California, Pennsylvania, Hawaii, Washington DC, and Puerto Rico itself. Other notable prints date from the Civil Rights Movement in 1963 and 1964, including voter registration drives, school boycotts, and the March on Washington; the Chamorro Documentary Project, with photographs from Guam in 1990; and Espada's documentation of HIV and drug use in San Francisco. Photographs include original descriptive titles.
  Prints have been boxed by size, with photographs grouped within boxes as best as possible by content (Puerto Rican Diaspora project materials have been sub-grouped by location, if possible). Prints are listed by the size of the box, which closely reflects the size of the print (15x19 prints are within a 16x20 box, for example). Some prints were assigned a number by Espada as part of his internal documentation. These have been included when present on the print.
  - 11x14 Boxes
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - Voter Registration, 1964, (19 prints) (Box 29-30)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project (Box 31)
      - New York: PROMESA (Box 31)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project (Box 32)
      - New York: PROMESA (Box 32)
  - 24x30 Box
    - HIV Project/Sex for Crack/San Francisco
      - Marilyn, The Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 35)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - Pennsylvania: Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 35)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - "Freedom in 63", Washington, DC, 1963 (Box 35)
    - Other projects
      - Abuelita, The Cloisters, New York City, 1961 (Box 35)
      - East New York, Brooklyn, 1963 (Box 35)
      - Washington, DC, 1973 (Box 35)
  - 16x20 Box (Box 36)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New Jersey: Don Pedro, former migrant worker, Vineland, 1982 (Print 148) (Box 36)
      - California: Salsa at Cabrillo Beach, San Juan Day Festival, 1976 (Print 254) (Box 36)
      - Connecticut: David, Hartford, 1981 (Box 36)
      - Connecticut: Hartford, 1981 (Box 36)
      - Connecticut: Hartford, 1981 (Box 36)
      - Connecticut: Roberto Laboy, former gang member, Hartford, 1981 (Print 131) (Box 36)
      - Connecticut: Comerio Restaurant, Park Street, Hartford, 1981 (Print 102) (Box 36)
    - HIV Project/Sex for Crack/San Francisco
      - Stephanie, Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 36)
      - Stephanie, The Mission, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 36)
      - Doris, Transvestite, The Mission, San Francisco, 1991 (Box 36)
      - Felipe, The Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 36)
      - Gumercindo, Former Dock Worker/Organizer, San Francisco, 1981 (Box 36)
      - Outreach worker with clients, The Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1989 (Box 36)
      - Suzie, The Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (signed by Espada) (Box 36)
      - Tenderloin (AIDS Hotel), San Francisco, 1990 (Box 36)
      - Shirley Green, Fire Survivor, The Mission, 1990 (Box 36)
      - John Henry, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 36)
      - Kathy at Mission Safe House, 1990 (Box 36)
  - 16x20 Box (Box 37)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New York: Going to Puerto Rico for the first time, New York City, 1972 (Print 107) (Box 37)
      - New York: Sandwich assembly line, food processing plant, South Bronx, 1981 (Print 105) (Box 37)
      - New York: Students at Boricua College, a bilingual bi-cultural institution, Brooklyn, 1983 (Print 221) (Box 37)
      - New York: Reading time in a bilingual classroom, East Harlem, 1982 (Print 121) (Box 37)
      - Puerto Rico: 1982 (Box 37)
      - Puerto Rico: Ismael and Ana Aponte, returned migrants, after 30 years in Patterson, NJ, at their new home in Barrio Pasto Seco, Rio Piedras, 1981 (Print 39) (Box 37)
      - Puerto Rico: Ismael Aponte, Jr., native of Patterson, NJ, son of returned migrants, at home in Barrio Pasto Seco, Las Piedras, 1981 (Print 12) (Box 37)
      - Puerto Rico: Jeanette and Danny Martinez and family, returned migrants, Maunabo, 1981 (Print 124) (Box 37)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - East New York, Brooklyn, 1964 (Box 37)
      - East New York, 1964 (Box 37)
      - School Boycott, Brooklyn, 1964 (Box 37)
      - South Bronx, New York, 1974 (Box 37)
    - Other projects
      - Woman and child in window, Brooklyn, New York, 1963 (Box 37)
      - Central Park, New York, 1960 (Box 37)
      - Rockaway Avenue, Brooklyn, New York, 1954 (Box 37)
  - 16x20 Box (Box 38)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - Washington, DC: Young man with Puerto Rico t-shirt, Solidarity Day demonstration, 1981 (Print 98) (Box 38)
      - Wisconsin: Boxing program at Centro Unido, Milwaukee, 1983 (Print 218) (Box 38)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - Young man at March on Washington, 1963 (Box 38)
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      - Saipan: Wood worker, 1990 (Box 38)
    - Other projects
      - Undated, unlabeled (Box 38)
  - 20x24 Box (Box 39)
    - HIV Project/Sex for Crack/San Francisco
      - Marilyn #2, The Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 39)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New York: East Harlem, 1981 (Box 39)
      - New York: Williamsburg, Brooklyn, 1984 (Box 39)
      - Pennsylvania: Welding Instructor, Lancaster, 1981 (Box 39)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - East New York, Brooklyn, 1964, (2 prints) (Box 39)
      - Malcolm X, Brooklyn, 1964 (Box 39)
      - Malcolm's Audience, Brooklyn, 1964 (Box 39)
    - Other Projects
      - Man by a fence, Washington, DC, 1975 (Box 39)
  - 16x20 Box (Box 40)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - California: Sonny Arguinzoni, spiritual leader of Victory Temple, a Pentecostal congregation, with Bible students, Los Angeles, 1981 (Print 53) (Box 40)
      - Connecticut: Hartford, 1981 (Box 40)
      - Connecticut: Couple on their stoop, Hartford, 1982 (Print 142) (Box 40)
      - Connecticut: Angel, president of Young Nomads, Hartford, 1982 (Print 127) (Box 40)
      - Connecticut: Angel and Lenny on Word Street, Hartford, 1982 (Print 167) (Box 40)
      - Connecticut: Christ for Sale, Hartford, 1982 (Print 146), (2 copies) (Box 40)
      - Connecticut: Hartford, 1981 (Box 40)
      - Hawaii: Fans at Puerto Rican Softball League tournament, Honolulu, 1981 (Print 169) (Box 40)
      - New York: Patrolman Carlos Gonzales, New York Police Dept., in locker room of 79th precinct station house, Brooklyn, 1982 (Print 119) (Box 40)
      - New York: PROMESA, South Bronx, 1981 (Box 40)
      - New York: South Bronx, 1981 (Box 40)
      - New York: Homeless program resident at PROMESA, Bronx, 1983 (Print 244) (Box 40)
      - New York: PROMESA, South Bronx, 1974 (Box 40)
  - 16x20 Box (Box 41)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New York: Doris at PROMESA, South Bronx, undated (Box 41)
      - New York: Bilingual class, East Harlem, undated (Print 120) (Box 41)
      - New York: Waiting for mediator at PROMESA, South Bronx, 1981 (Box 41)
      - New York: Ballet Hispanico, 1981 (Print 191) (Box 41)
      - New York: Miriam Colon, 1982 (Box 41)
      - Pennsylvania: Cuco, outside fenced-in hardball court. "We fixed it up and they fenced us out," Harrisburg, 1979 (Print 184) (Box 41)
      - Pennsylvania: Cuco and friend, Harrisburg, 1979 (Print 7) (Box 41)
      - Pennsylvania: Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 41)
      - Pennsylvania: Philadelphia, 1982 (Print 214) (Box 41)
      - Puerto Rico: Barrio Tokio, San Juan, 1980 (Box 41)
      - Puerto Rico: Rosa Santiago, returned migrant, after 16 years in Lorain, Ohio. Barrio la Pica, Maunabo, 1981 (Print 16) (Box 41)
      - Puerto Rico: Avelino Reyes, returned migrant, with his cattle. Las Piedras, 1981 (Print 177) (Box 41)
      - Washington DC: Puerto Rican "Home Town" contingent, Hispanic Festival, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - March on Washington, 1963 (Box 41)
      - School boycott, during Malcolm X's speech, 1964 (Box 41)
    - Other projects
      - Sister Theresa, Pentecostal service, East New York, Brooklyn, 1965 (Print 152) (Box 41)
      - Maria, East New York, Brooklyn, 1965 (Print 188) (Box 41)
      - Jose Acuna, community organizer, in building burned by arson, Manhattan, New York, 1981 (Box 41)
      - Death car (Rose!), Rochester, New York, 1974 (Box 41)
  - 14x18 Box (Box 42)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - California: Pareja Tipica, celebrating San Juan Day, Cabrillo Beach, 1976 (Print 255) (Box 42)
      - California: David Santiago, civic leader, chair of El Dia de San Juan Festival at Cabrillo Beach, 1981 (Print 44) (Box 42)
      - California: Dona Lila Romero, early migrant (1926) to Arizona cotton fields, Oakland, 1981 (Print 24) (Box 42)
      - California: San Francisco, undated (Print 248) (Box 42)
      - California: Tommy Chevere, second generation, at his auto body repair shop, San Leondro, 1981 (Print 52) (Box 42)
      - Connecticut: Bridgeport, undated (Box 42)
      - Connecticut: Mercedes on her stoop, Word Street, Hartford, 1982 (Print 151) (Box 42)
      - Connecticut: El Piraguero, Park Street, Hartford, 1982 (Print 203) (Box 42)
      - Hawaii: Joe and Mina Velez, Big Island, 1981 (Box 42)
      - Hawaii: Blase Souza, second generation, historian of Puerto Rican experience in Hawaii, founder of Puerto Rican Heritage Society, Honolulu, 1981 (Print 62) (Box 42)
      - Hawaii: 1980 (Box 42)
      - Hawaii: Santa Rochyuez, first generation Hawaiian-Puerto Rican, in front of her lava oven, Kukuihaele Plantation, 1981 (Print 173) (Box 42)
      - Hawaii: Walter-Shinka house, a drug rehabilitation half-way house in Honolulu, 1981 (Print 91) (Box 42)
      - Hawaii: Confessor Riviera, second generation Hawaiian-Puerto Rican, with experimental cutting on his farm, Kona Coast of the Big Island (Print 3) (Box 42)
      - Massachusetts: Carlos Esteban, Puerto Rican ex-political prisoner in Chile, English teacher in community social program, Roxbury, 1979 (Print 49) (Box 42)
      - New Jersey: Eladio Rodriguez, proprietor of El Gallito Restaurant, Jersey City, 1982 (Print 113) (Box 42)
      - New York: Grace, resident at PROMESA, South Bronx, 1981 (Print 30) (Box 42)
      - New York: Alberto, resident at PROMESA, South Bronx, 1981 (Print 31) (Box 42)
      - Pennsylvania: Walton, mushroom worker organizer, Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 42)
  - 14x18 Box (Box 43)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New York: PROMESA, South Bronx, undated (Box 43)
      - New York: Grace, resident of PROMESA, South Bronx, 1981 (duplicate of Print 30) (Box 43)
      - New York: Miriam Colon, founder and director of Puerto Rican Traveling Theatre, 1981 (Print 40) (Box 43)
      - New York: Manhattan Valley, undated (Box 43)
      - New York: Going to Puerto Rico for the first time, New York City (duplicate of Print 107) (Box 43)
      - New York: Young boy with baby carriage, East New York, Brooklyn, 1965 (Box 43)
      - Ohio: Making a point: Meeting at the Spanish-American committee to discuss a meeting with the mayor, Cleveland, 1979 (Print 223) (Box 43)
      - Pennsylvania: Gumercindo at mushroom farm, Kennett Square, 1981 (Print 59) (Box 43)
      - Pennsylvania: Manuel and Hazel Molina. He is a native of Puerto Rico and a permanent worker at a mushroom farm; She is a self-described hill-billy, Kennett Square, 1981 (Print 75a) (Box 43)
      - Pennsylvania: Marcelino Martinez, foreman at mushroom farm, Kennett Square, 1981 (Print 137) (Box 43)
      - Pennsylvania: Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 43)
      - Pennsylvania: Angelita Inizarry, migrant agricultural worker, Kennett Square, 1981 (Print 57), (2 copies) (Box 43)
      - Puerto Rico: Angel Rosano, returned migrant, after a lifetime in the South Bronx, at home with her hens, Camuy, 1981 (Print 205) (Box 43)
      - Puerto Rico: Destiny Crew, children of returned migrants, at their "hot corners" at Roman Power High School, Las Piedras, 1981 (Print 199) (Box 43)
      - Puerto Rico: El Dueno de la Plaza, Humacao, 1981 (Print 101) (Box 43)
      - Puerto Rico: Manuel Garcia, returned migrant and fourth generation fisherman, Luguillo, 1981 (Print 82) (Box 43)
      - Unnamed, undated (Box 43)
  - 11x14 Box (Box 44)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - Voter Registration, Brownsville, Brooklyn, undated (Box 44)
    - HIV Project/Sex for Crack/San Francisco
      - Piri Thomas, San Francisco, 1985 (Box 44)
      - John Santos, renowned musician and musicologist, San Francisco, 1980 (Box 44)
      - Michael at Thor Hotel, Mission Agenda, San Francisco, 1986 (Box 44)
      - The Mission, San Francisco, undated (Box 44)
    - Youth Environment Study (YES)
      - Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 44)
      - Tenderloin, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 44)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - Connecticut: Hartford, 1981, (4 prints) (Box 44)
      - Connecticut: Hartford, 1982, (5 prints) (Box 44)
      - Connecticut: Hartford, undated, (3 prints) (Box 44)
      - Connecticut: Savage nomads, Hartford, 1981 (Box 44)
      - Connecticut: Ricky Savage Nomad, Hartford, 1982 (Box 44)
      - Connecticut: Young nomads, Hartford, 1981 (Box 44)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      Titles are from original descriptions.
      - Terry's Chamorro Food Counter, Guam, 1990 (Box 45)
      - "Cantan Chamorritas": singing group, Guam, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Lunch break under the trees, Guam, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Boy on bicycle in front of church, Guam, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Above ground cemetery, Guam, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Cathedral with statue in front, Guam, 1990 (Box 45)
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - Chicago: 1980 (Box 45)
      - New Jersey: Jersey City, 1981 (Box 45)
      - New Jersey: Newark, undated (Box 45)
      - New York: East Harlem, 1974, (3 prints, one is in mat) (Box 45)
      - New York: East Harlem, 1981, (2 prints) (Box 45)
      - New York: Manhattan Valley, 1981, (2 prints) (Box 45)
      - New York: Ballet Hispanico, 1981 [in mat] (Box 45)
      - New York: Ballet Hispanico, 1982 (Box 45)
      - New York: Manhattan Valley, 1982 (Box 45)